purposegames.com 2019-07-13

# PurposeGames - Privacy Policy - PurposeGames

Effective May 21, 2018

PurposeGames.com is a site that allows its user to contribute content. When doing so, we demand that anyone who creates games, challenges, or other services offered on the site, registers with the site. For anything and everything else, you can stay unregistered and completely anonymous should you wish to do so.

## Your privacy is critically important to us. At PurposeGames we have a few fundamental principles

  * For just visiting our site and playing our games, we **do not ask you for personal information**. Ever. If you want to create your own games we need to ask for your e-mail address, and we allow for you to disclose a bit more about yourself in your profile pages, but such information is completely optional.

  * Should you have given us any information, we don’t share your such information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.

  * In our gaming engines, creating games, we aim to make it as simple as possible for you to control what’s visible to the public, kept private, and permanently deleted. However, we do not control search engines out there so we cannot guarantee what will show up when people search for your games on search engines on the internet.

## Website Visitors

Like most website operators, PurposeGames collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. PurposeGames' purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how PurposeGames’ visitors use its website. From time to time, PurposeGames may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Aside from the geo-location, e-mail, and movement pattern on the site, we do not collect nor use any other information provided by you as a user. We will never share your e-mail address with anyone. We may, on occasion, contact you via your e-mail address with information about the PurposeGames services.

We use Google Analytics and Google's Advertising Products. To get a complete picture of what they are collecting, please view [How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/partners/)

PurposeGames collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on PurposeGames.com. We never share that data unless we are provided to do so by law. The reasons for logging such data is to provide a secure environment for as many as possibly, thereby giving us the possibility to block any wrong doers, based on the IP from which they are connecting to PurposeGames.com.

## Ads

**Please see GDPR Specific details (EU visitors only) below in section "EU Specific Ad Settings"**

Ads appearing on any of our websites may be delivered to users by advertising partners, who may set cookies. These cookies allow the ad server to recognize your computer each time they send you an online advertisement to compile information about you or others who use your computer. This information allows ad networks to, among other things, deliver targeted advertisements that they believe will be of most interest to you. This Privacy Policy covers the use of cookies by PurposeGames and does not cover the use of cookies by any advertisers. You can view how Google is using their cookies here: [How Google uses data when you use our partners' sites or apps](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites). 

  * Third party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to your website or other websites.
  * Google's use of advertising cookies enables it and its partners to serve ads to your users based on their visit to your sites and/or other sites on the Internet.
  * You may opt out of personalized advertising by visiting Google [Ads Settings](https://www.google.com/settings/ads). 

### EU Specific Ad Settings

Visitors from the EU-countries will be shown a consent form to accept personalized ads after May 25, 2018 as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) takes effect across the European Union. By not accepting, or opting out of personalized ads, the user is still shown ads only not personalized. You can read more about this and opt in or out of personalized ads on PurposeGames [in our privacy center](https://www.purposegames.com/privacy-center).

## Cookies

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. PurposeGames uses cookies to help PurposeGames identify and track visitors, their usage of PurposeGames website, and their website access preferences. PurposeGames visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using PurposeGames.com website, with the drawback that certain features of PurposeGames websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

We have implemented Google Analytics features based on Display Advertising ([Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2799357?hl=en)). You can [opt-out](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) of Google Analytics for Display Advertising and customize Google Display Network ads using the Ads Settings. In addition, you can use the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-on](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/) to disable tracking by Google Analytics. We will use the data provided by Google Analytics Demographics and Interest Reporting to develop the site and content around our users’ interests.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, PurposeGames may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in PurposeGames' sole discretion. PurposeGames encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.
